For logistic regression, we previously
针对逻辑回归问题
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
talked about two types of optimization algorithms.
我们在之前的课程已经学习过两种优化算法
We talked about how to use
我们首先学习了
gradient descent to optimize as cost function J of theta.
使用梯度下降法来优化代价函数 J(θ)
And we also talked about
接下来学习了
advanced optimization methods.
更高级的优化算法
Ones that require that you
这些高级优化算法
provide a way to compute
需要你自己设计
your cost function J of
代价函数 J(θ)
theta and that you provide a way to compute the derivatives.
自己计算导数
In this video, we'll show how
在本节课中
you can adapt both of
我们将展示
those techniques, both gradient descent and
如何改进梯度下降法和
the more advanced optimization techniques
高级优化算法
in order to have them
使其能够应用于
work for regularized logistic regression.
正则化的逻辑回归
So, here's the idea.
接下来我们来学习其中的原理
We saw earlier that Logistic
在之前的课程中我们注意到
Regression can also be prone
对于逻辑回归问题
to overfitting if you fit
有可能会出现过拟合的现象
it with a very, sort of,
如果你使用了
high order polynomial features like this.
类似这样的高阶多项式
Where G is the
g 是 S 型函数
sigmoid function and in
具体来说
particular you end up with
最后你会得到这样的结果
a hypothesis, you know,
whose decision bound to be
分类边界看起来是一个
just sort of an overly complex
过于复杂并且
and extremely contortive function that
十分扭曲的函数
really isn't such a great
针对这个训练点集
hypothesis for this training
这显然不是一个好的结果
set, and more generally if you have
通常情况下
logistic regression with a lot of features.
如果要解决的逻辑回归问题有很多参数
Not necessarily polynomial ones, but
并且又用了过多的多项式项
just with a lot of
这些项大部分都是没有必要的
features you can end up with overfitting.
最终都可能出现过拟合的现象
This was our cost function for logistic regression.
这是逻辑回归问题的代价函数
And if we want to modify
为了将其修改为正则化形式
it to use regularization, all we
need to do is add to
我们只需要在后面增加一项
it the following term
plus londer over 2M, sum
加上 λ/2m
from J equals 1, and
再跟过去一样
as usual sum from J equals 1.
这个求和将 j 从1开始
Rather than the sum from J
而不是从0开始
equals 0, of theta J squared.
累积 θj 的平方
And this has to
增加的这一项
effect therefore, of penalizing
将惩罚参数 θ1, θ2 等等
the parameters theta 1 theta
一直到 θn
2 and so on up to theta N from being too large.
防止这些参数取值过大
And if you do this,
增加了这一项之后
then it will the have the
产生的效果是
effect that even though you're fitting
即使用有很多参数的
a very high order polynomial with a lot of parameters.
高阶多项式来拟合
So long as you apply regularization
只要使用了正则化方法
and keep the parameters small
约束这些参数使其取值很小
you're more likely to get a decision boundary.
你仍有可能得到一条
You know, that maybe looks more like this.
看起来是这样的分类边界
It looks more reasonable for separating
显然  这条边界更合理地
the positive and the negative examples.
分开了正样本和负样本
So, when using regularization
因此  在使用了正则化方法以后
even when you have a lot
即使你的问题有很多参数
of features, the regularization can
正则化方法可以帮你
help take care of the overfitting problem.
避免过拟合的现象
How do we actually implement this?
这到底是怎样实现的呢？
Well, for the original gradient descent
首先看看以前学过的梯度下降法
algorithm, this was the update we had.
这是我们之前得到的更新式
We will repeatedly perform the following
我们利用这个式子
update to theta J. This
迭代更新 θj
slide looks a lot like the previous one for linear regression.
这一页幻灯片看起来和上一节课的线性回归问题很像
But what I'm going to do is
但是这里我将
write the update for theta 0 separately.
θ0 的更新公式单独写出来
So, the first line is
第一行用来更新 θ0
for update for theta 0 and
a second line is now
第二行用来更新
my update for theta 1
θ1 到 θn
up to theta N.
Because I'm going to treat theta 0 separately.
将 θ0 单独处理
And in order to
为了按照
modify this algorithm, to use
正则化代价函数的形式
a regularized cos function,
来修改算法
all I need to do is
接下来的推导
pretty similar to what we
非常类似于
did for linear regression is
上一节学习过的正则化线性回归
actually to just modify this
只需要将第二个式子
second update rule as follows.
修改成这样
And, once again, this, you know,
我们又一次发现
cosmetically looks identical what
修改后的式子表面上看起来
we had for linear regression.
与上一节的线性回归问题很相似
But of course is not the
但是实质上这与
same algorithm as we had,
我们上节学过的算法并不一样
because now the hypothesis
因为现在的假设 h(x)
is defined using this.
是按照这个式子定义的
So this is not the same algorithm
这与上一节正则化线性回归算法
as regularized linear regression.
中的定义并不一样
Because the hypothesis is different.
由于假设的不同
Even though this update that I wrote down.
我写下的迭代公式
It actually looks cosmetically the
只是表面上看起来很像
same as what we had earlier.
上一节学过的
We're working out gradient descent for regularized linear regression.
正则化线性回归问题中的梯度下降算法
And of course, just to wrap
总结一下
up this discussion, this term
here in the square
方括号中的这一项
brackets, so this term
here, this term is,
这一项是
of course, the new partial
新的代价函数 J(θ)
derivative for respect of
关于 θj 的偏导数
theta J of the new cost function J of theta.
Where J of theta here is
这里的 J(θ)
the cost function we defined on
是我们在上一页幻灯片中
a previous slide that does use regularization.
定义的 使用了正则化的代价函数
So, that's gradient descent for regularized linear regression.
以上就是正则化逻辑回归问题的梯度下降算法
Let's talk about how to
接下来我们讨论
get regularized linear regression
如何在更高级的优化算法中
to work using the more
使用同样的
advanced optimization methods.
正则化技术
And just to remind you for
提醒一下
those methods what we needed
对于这些高级算法
to do was to define the
我们需要自己定义
function that's called the cost
costFuntion 函数
function, that takes us
这个函数有一个输入参数
input the parameter vector theta and
向量 theta
once again in the equations
theta 的内容是这样的
we've been writing here we used 0 index vectors.
我们的参数索引依然从0开始
So we had theta 0 up
即 θ0 到 θn
to theta N. But
但是由于 Octave 中
because Octave indexes the vectors starting from 1.
向量索引是从1开始
Theta 0 is written
我们的参数是从 θ0 到 θn
in Octave as theta 1.
在 Octave 里 是从 theta(1) 开始标号的
Theta 1 is written in
而 θ1 将被记为 theta(2)
Octave as theta 2, and
以此类推
so on down to theta
直到 θn 被记为
N plus 1.
theta(n+1)
And what we needed to
而我们需要做的
do was provide a function.
就是将这个自定义代价函数
Let's provide a function called
这个 costFunction 函数
cost function that we would
代入到我们之前学过的
then pass in to what we have, what we saw earlier.
We will use the fminunc
fminunc函数中
and then
括号里面是 @costFunction
you know at cost function,
将 @costFunction 作为参数代进去
and so on, right.
等等
But the F min, u
fminunc返回的是
and c was the F min
函数 costFunction
unconstrained and this will
在无约束条件下的最小值
work with fminunc
因此  这个式子
was what will take
将求得代价函数的最小值
the cost function and minimize it for us.
So the two main things that
因此 costFunction 函数
the cost function needed to
有两个返回值
return were first J-val.
第一个是 jVal
And for that, we need
为此  我们要在这里
to write code to
补充代码
compute the cost function J of theta.
来计算代价函数 J(θ)
Now, when we're using regularized logistic
由于我们在这使用的是正则化逻辑回归
regression, of course the
因此
cost function j of theta
代价函数 J(θ) 也相应需要改变
changes and, in particular,
具体来说
now a cost function needs to
代价函数需要
include this additional regularization term at the end as well.
增加这一正则化项
So, when you compute j of
因此  当你在计算 J(θ) 时
theta be sure to include that term at the end.
需要确保包含了最后这一项
And then, the other thing that
另外 代价函数的
this cost function thing
另一项返回值是
needs to derive with a gradient.
对应的梯度导数
So gradient one needs
梯度的第一个元素
to be set to the
gradient(1) 就等于
partial derivative of J
J(θ) 关于 θ0 的偏导数
of theta with respect to theta
J(θ)关于θ0的偏导数
zero, gradient two needs
梯度的第二个元素按照这个式子计算
to be set to that, and so on.
剩余元素以此类推
Once again, the index is off by one.
再次强调 向量元素索引是从1开始
Right, because of the indexing from
这是因为 Octave 的向量索引
one Octave users.
就是从1开始的
And looking at these terms.
再来总结一下
This term over here.
首先看第一个公式
We actually worked this out
在之前的课程中
on a previous slide is actually equal to this.
我们已经计算过它等于这个式子
It doesn't change.
这个式子没有变化
Because the derivative for theta zero doesn't change.
因为相比没有正则化的版本
Compared to the version without regularization.
J(θ) 关于 θ0 的偏导数不会改变
And the other terms do change.
但是其他的公式确实有变化
And in particular the derivative respect to theta one.
以 θ1 的偏导数为例
We worked this out on the previous slide as well.
在之前的课程里我们也计算过这一项
Is equal to, you know,
它等于这个式子
the original term and then minus
减去 λ 除以 m (这里应为加 校对者注)
londer M times theta 1.
再乘以 θ1
Just so we make sure we pass this correctly.
注意要确保这段代码编写正确
And we can add parentheses here.
建议在这里添加括号
Right, so the summation doesn't extend.
防止求和符号的作用域扩大
And similarly, you know,
类似的
this other term here looks
再来看这个式子
like this, with this additional
相比于之前的幻灯片
term that we had on
这里多了额外的一项
the previous slide, that corresponds to
这就是正则化后的
the gradient from their regularization objective.
梯度计算方法
So if you implement this
当你自己定义了
cost function and pass
costFunction 函数
this into fminunc
并将其传递到 fminuc
or to one of those advanced optimization
或者其他类似的高级优化函数中
techniques, that will minimize
就可以求出
the new regularized cost function J of theta.
这个新的正则化代价函数的极小值
And the parameters you get out
而返回的参数值
will be the ones that correspond to
即是对应的
logistic regression with regularization.
逻辑回归问题的正则化解
So, now you know
讲到这里  你应该已经学会了
how to implement regularized logistic regression.
解决正则化逻辑回归问题的方法
When I walk around Silicon Valley,
你知道吗 我住在硅谷
I live here in Silicon Valley, there are
当我在硅谷晃悠时
a lot of engineers that are frankly, making
我看到许多工程师
a ton of money for their
运用机器学习算法
companies using machine learning algorithms.
给他们公司挣来了很多金子
And I know we've
课讲到这里
only been, you know, studying this stuff for a little while.
大家对机器学习算法可能还只是略懂
But if you understand linear
但是一旦你精通了
regression, the advanced optimization
线性回归、高级优化算法
algorithms and regularization, by
和正则化技术
now, frankly, you probably know
坦率地说
quite a lot more machine learning
你对机器学习的理解
than many, certainly now,
可能已经比许多工程师深入了
but you probably know quite a
现在  你已经有了
lot more machine learning right now
丰富的机器学习知识
than frankly, many of the
目测比那些硅谷工程师还厉害
Silicon Valley engineers out there having very successful careers.
而那些工程师都混得还不错
You know, making tons of money for the companies.
给他们公司挣了大钱 你懂的
Or building products using machine learning algorithms.
或者用机器学习算法来做产品
So, congratulations.
所以 恭喜你
You've actually come a long ways.
你已经历练得差不多了
And you can actually, you
已经具备足够的知识
actually know enough to
足够将这些算法
apply this stuff and get to work for many problems.
用于解决实际问题
So congratulations for that.
所以你可以小小的骄傲一下了
But of course, there's
但是
still a lot more that we
我还是有很多可以教你们的
want to teach you, and in
the next set of videos after
接下来的课程中
this, we'll start to talk
我们将学习
about a very powerful cause of non-linear classifier.
一个非常强大的非线性分类器
So whereas linear regression, logistic
无论是线性回归问题
regression, you know, you can
还是逻辑回归问题
form polynomial terms, but it
都可以构造多项式来解决
turns out that there are much
但是 你将逐渐发现还有
more powerful nonlinear quantifiers that
更强大的非线性分类器
can then sort of polynomial regression.
可以用来解决多项式回归问题
And in the next set
在下一节课
of videos after this one, I'll start telling you about them.
我将向大家介绍它们
So that you have even more
你将学会
powerful learning algorithms than you have
比你现在解决问题的方法
now to apply to different problems.
强大N倍的学习算法